Curriculum Vitae - John Croker

Web Developer

Website: johncroker.me

Technology Stack

PHP, Laravel, Node.js, Express, es6, jQuery, CSS3 (SASS/LESS), Gulp, MS/MySQL, Windows Server.

Personal Statement

Web Developer with 3 years experience building efficient and engaging web applications. I have worked on numerous projects including simple landing pages, bespoke Customer Relationship Management (CRM) systems and news blogs. I take pride in coding to the best of my ability while I constantly strive to learn more and keep up with industry trends and best practices.

Relevant Experience

Web Developer - Barcadia Media (2015 - present)

I am one of two in-house developers working in tandem to build and maintain web applications related to the UK Finance industry. To begin with my role was front end focused but has grown to be full stack whilst learning from the senior developer. The role utilized technologies including Windows Server, MS/MySQL, PHP, Laravel, es6, jQuery and CSS. Further responsibilities include building HTML email campaigns as well as providing general IT support to the office.

My daily workflow is often 'ad hoc' requiring me to switch between working on long-term projects, quick feature additions and hotfixes to live applications both internally and for clients. Looming deadlines often suddenly appear requiring me to work quickly and put in the extra hours to make sure a project is finished on time.

Freelance Web Developer - Buxton Web Design Ltd. (2015)

Acted in a support capacity working on Wordpress websites; with a primary focus on improving user experience (UX) via CSS and Javascript.

Freelance Web Developer - BBPN ltd. (2014 - 2015)

The role mainly involved maintaining and adding functionality to Wordpress websites owned by the company. My main achievement was creating a Wordpress plugin allowing users to build bespoke guotes for services the business offered.

Education

Lancaster University (2011 - 2014)

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science - First Class Honours

Blackpool and Fylde College (2009 - 2011)

IT Practitioner BTEC Diploma (Distinction)

References

Andy Shields - Director - Barcadia Media

- → andy@barcadiamedia.co.uk
- **→** 01253 272998

Mike Knudsen - Director - BBPN

- → mike@bbpn.co.uk
- **→** 07515173050

Andrew Wearden - Director - Buxton Web Design

- → andrew@buxtonwebdesign.co.uk
- **→** 01298 71821